Guide to the Cornell University Treasurer's Office Accounts, 1866-1944
Cornell University Treasurer's Office Accounts, 1866-1944
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University Treasurer's Office Accounts, 1866-1944.
7-6-13
Cornell University.Treasurer's Office.
35.6 cubic feet; 248 volumes.
Account books, records, indexes, ledgers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Legal files, credit books, cash books, vouchers, fund reports, contracts, bids, and many other financial records of the University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Legal files, credit books, cash books, vouchers, fund reports, contracts, bids, and many other financial records of the University.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Cornell University--Finances.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Restricted to permission of the Office of Origin.
RELATED MATERIALS
Includes collection #7-1-1610, 7-7-1636, 7-1-1345, 7-6-86, 7-6-425, 7-6-13, and 7-6-1110.
Account books, bond books, mortgage books.
CONTAINER LIST
- 20 Small cash Account Books with First National Bank of Ithaca, 1886 -1911 (Box 1)
- 1 Small cash Account Book with Fifth Avenue Trust Company, New York City, 1904-1910 (Box 1)
- 1 Small Journal of Accounts (Investments, Bonds and Stocks) n.d. (Box 1)
- Account book, 1911-1913 (Volume 1)
  Listing all the expenses of the various departments of the University from May 1911 to Mar. 1914. The listings are by departments and identify the appropriation from which each sum was taken.
- Records of Bonds, 1880-1914 (Volume 2)
  A listing of university held bonds from Oct. 30, 1880 through June 27, 1914. Lists issuing company, type of bond, number issue date, date and place payable, interest payable and principal.
- Records of interest payments on mortgages, 1900-1915 (Volume 3)
- Records of mortgages, 1876-1915 (Volume 4)
  Mortgages book giving complete data on mortgages held by the university from 1876 to 1915. Lists purchase data, mortgagee amount of cash involved, interest rate and date. Also from whom purchased if purchased, and where recorded and where payable.
- Record of interest payments on bonds, 1900-1915 (Volume 5)
- Index of Mortgages, n.d. (Volume 6)
  Index to university mortgage books. No dates. Gives name of mortgage and page number in the entire book.
- Record of Bonds, 1880-1931; also, Record of mortgages 1876-1900 (Volume 7)
  List of mortgages financed by the university from Apr. 10, 1876 to Jan. 4, 1900. Back of volume contains same listing for bonds from May 8, 1880 to Jan. 12, 1900. This book lists complete information on both bonds and mortgages.
- Index (?) (Volume 8)
- Index of Mortgages, n.d. (Volume 9)
  Mortgage and bond book listing the various persons against whom mortgages and bonds were held. It contains an index and all listings are alphabetically arranged along with the folio numbers and amount of cash involved. There are no dates.
- Record of Securities, 1872-1890 (Volume 10)
  A listing of the securities in which the university endowment funds were invested. Listed are the purchased date, firm, type of security, number of security, date issued, when payable, amount of interest.
- Cash book (outgoing), 1897-1913 (Volume 11)
  Day book listing daily payments from Aug. 6, 1899 to Feb. 1913. Entries are intermittently placed throughout the book.
- Index of Securities (Volume 12)
- C.U. Appropriation book, 1900-1920 (Volume 13)
  University appropriations book 1900-1920. Lists two years to a page, moneys appropriated for university expenses by department. Lists amount of appropriation, expenditure and balance of appropriation left after each entry.
- C.U. Reports, 1864-1868 (Removed - see Acc. 47-1-1527) (Volume 14)
- Records of Special Funds, 1879-1885 (Volume 15)
  University ledger listing: 1) University land script fund, 2) University endowment, 3) Various university funds. These entries cover the dates, Feb. 1879 to June 1885 by month and by separate fund.
- General Ledger A, 1868-1871 (Volume 16)
  Ledger listing the various expenses in an itemized form which the various departments of the university and persons concerned with the university incurred from Nov. 25, 1868 to Aug. 31, 1871. Contains an index.
- College of Forestry - Voucher Records, 1899-1914 (Volume 17)
  Voucher record-College Forest Appropriation Book. Sixty pages of voucher listings by number from 1 to 780. Dates extend from May 20, 1899 to Apr. 22, 1914. Each entry describes the person date the sum concerned was appropriated and total of the full appropriation from which the sum was taken.
- College of Forestry - Voucher Record, 1898-1903 (Volume 18)
  Voucher Record-College Forest Appropriations. Lists date, amount of bill paid and total amount of appropriation from which money was taken. May 12, 1898 to Oct. 17, 1903.
- Professional Pension Recod, 1903-1944 (Volume 19)
  Account book listing professional pension fund payments, by professors name from 1903 to 1947. Index of back cover.
- Student Loan Fund, 1873-1904 (Volume 20)
  Student Loan Fund book. Students and sums are listed by name from 1873-1904.
- Record of Sage College Room Rents, 1895-1900 (Volume 21)
  Sage College Record of Room Rent 1895-1900. Listings are made by person, monthly.
- Abstracts of Ithaca property owned by Ezra Cornell and Cornell University (Volume 22)
  Seventy-three pages of titles, abstracts, maps and descriptions of various land in and about Ithaca which were transferred through Ezra Cornell to the university. These abstracts have record of land as early as 1822 and extend up to 1867. The various mortgages on the land are also described.
- Account Book (Day Book), 1886-1871 (Volume 23)
- Account Book (Day Book), 1871-1879 (Volume 24)
- Account Book (Day Book), 1869-1871; Coal Contracts, 1871-1888 (Volume 25)
- Account Book (Day Book), 1866-1871 (Volume 26)
- Account Book (Day Book), 1870-1871 (Volume 27)
- University budget, 1871-1900 (Volume 28)
- Agriculture and Home Eco. disbursements, 1926-1927 (Volume 29)
- General Ledger D, 1890-1904 (Volume 30)
- Account Book (Cash Book No. 2), 1882-1891 (Volume 31)
- Cash Book No. 3, 1891-1896 (Volume 32)
- Ledger - Account Book, 1879-1890 (Volume 33)
- Letter book - orders, 1889-1893 (Volume 34)
- Letter book - orders, 1893-1895 (Volume 35)
- Letter book - orders, 1891-1897 (Volume 36)
- Letter book - orders, 1897-1899 (Volume 37)
- Letter book - orders, 1899-1901 (Volume 38)
- Letter book - orders, 1902-1904 (Volume 39)
- Letter book - orders, 1904 (Volume 40)